(约翰尼·英格力士)
Johnny English.
约翰尼·英格力士
Five years ago, he was our top agent.
五年前 他是我们最好的特工
Yeah. Took his eye off the ball in Mozambique.
对 要不是他在莫桑比克惹了麻烦
(军情七处一团糟)
(卫生部-莫桑比克 军情七处在非洲的大灾难)
Does it have to be him?
难道非他不可吗
He's the only one our contact will talk to.
线人只肯跟他接头
So where is he?
他现在在哪
(西藏群山)
You came here to forget your life of shame.
你来这儿是为了抛开耻辱的过往
But the path you must tread
但你的重生之路
to new life will be not be easy, English.
实非易事 英格力士
Our purpose here is simple.
我们的目标很明确
To strengthen what is weak.
就是化弱为强
Make hard what is soft.
化软为硬
This will take time.
这一切都需要时间
Mind must be master of the body.
意志是身体的主人
Strong mind can separate the body from its suffering.
顽强的意志 何惧上刀山下火海
Good concentration, English.
集中精神 英格力士
Sorry? Hot! Hot! Hot! Hot!
什么 烫烫烫
You are not young.
你虽青春不再
But with age comes wisdom.
但姜还是老的辣
When mind is master of the body,
若然意志能控制好身体
you will be warrior once more.
你定能重出江湖
Master, what is my destiny?
大师 我前路何如
I'm in touch with a higher power.
我和更高层联系过
MI7 wants you on the first flight back to London.
军情七处希望你搭最快的航班回伦敦
Master, am I ready?
大师 我准备好了吗
No.
为时尚早
Window seat or aisle?
靠窗还是走道
(旅客: 英格力士 | 座位号: 6A 靠窗)
(目的地: 伦敦 | 出发地: 西藏)
(红海)
(索马里)
(突尼斯)
(扫描中)
(目的地: 伦敦)
(东芝 英国情报局)
One moment, please. Good morning, sir.
请稍等 先生 早上好
Toshiba British Intelligence.
东芝英国情报局
For electronic products press one.
需要电子产品请按一
To speak to an agent, press two.
连线特工请按二
Certainly, sir. Can I redirect you to our website?
当然 先生 麻烦您重新输入我们的网址好吗
www.spyingforyou.gov.uk
Toshiba British Intelligence.
东芝英国情报局
Good morning, sir. Can I help you?
先生 早上好 有什么能帮助您的
Johnny English.
约翰尼·英格力士
Pegasus is expecting you.
帕加索斯在等你
Look into the camera.
请看镜头
Don't smile.
别笑
《憨豆特工2》
Pamela Thornton, Head of MI7.
帕姆拉·桑顿 军情七处的总管
Johnny English.
约翰尼·英格力士
Have a seat.
请坐
You've been away for some time, English.
你走了有一段时间了 英格力士
But you haven't been forgotten.
我们可没忘记你
Come on.
走开
People here often talk about your adventures in Mozambique.
这里还常说起你在莫桑比克的冒险
Well, MI7 has come a long way since then.
军情七处从你走后又进步了许多
The guns, the fast cars,
什么枪战 飞车
and the chauvinism are all on their way out.
沙文主义那一套 都过时了
Frankly, I didn't want to see you back.
坦白说 我不乐意看到你回来
You are everything I came into this service to change.
你就是我要改革的东西
But my hands are tied.
可惜这事我做不了主
And there are times when
总有些时候
one has to go against one's better judgement.
人会和明智的抉择背道而驰
We have a situation.
我们有个新情况
Indeed.
不错
There's a good puss. There's a good puss.
这有只乖猫咪 有只乖猫咪
There's a good pussy. Who's a good pussy?
这有只乖猫咪 她是谁
- I'm impressed. - Who's a good pussy?
- 我很意外 - 她是谁
Philby never lets strangers pick him up.
菲白从不让陌生人抱它
I'm very much at one with the animal kingdom.
在动物世界里 我总能获得特权
There's a good puss. I know, I know.
这有只乖猫咪 我知道 我知道
Who's lovely? Who's lovely?
谁是小可爱 小可爱是谁
Who...
谁...
We're all lovely.
我们都是小可爱
Kate Sumner, our behavioural psychologist.
凯特·萨姆纳 行为治疗师
I've heard a great deal about you.
久仰您的大名
Glowing reports, I trust.
想必都是盛赞
Tell me, Ms. Sumner,
跟我说说 萨姆纳女士
what exactly does a behavioral psychologist do?
行为治疗师的工作是什么
Monitor observable behavior for signs of internal psychology.
观察深层心理的外在表象
We read people.
我们读人
Well, we must get together sometime.
找时间聚聚
I think you'll find me a real page-turner.
你肯定会觉得我是本好书
So, Pegasus, this situation.
帕加索斯 说说现况吧
Ex-CIA agent Titus Fisher
前中情局特工提图斯·费舍尔
has contacted us from Hong Kong.
从香港联系我们
He has intelligence of a plot to assassinate the Chinese Premier
他的情报显示 有人要在下周的中英会谈时
at the Anglo-Chinese talks next week.
暗杀中国总理
We need you to go and find out what he's got.
需要你去弄清他确切的情报内容
Well, in that case, Pegasus, count me in.
既然如此 帕加索斯 我去
Agent One will meet you downstairs.
一号特工会在楼下见你
So, I just scaled the walls,
结果 我就爬上墙头
blew the whole place to kingdom come.
把那鬼地方炸成平地
An hour later I'm sitting
一小时后
in the bar with a White Russian in my hand.
我已经手拿鸡尾酒坐在酒吧里
Who was very lovely, too, I can tell you.
跟你们说 那也是相当惬意
Simon.
西蒙
Hello, Johnny!
你好 约翰尼
Simon,
西蒙
you look wonderful. But, then, you always did.
春风得意啊 不过你一向如此
Welcome back. How long has it been?
欢迎回来 你走了多久
I don't know.
不知道
Five years, three months and six days, or something.
五年三个月又六天 左右吧
Of course, Mozambique.
当然 莫桑比克
That was a balls-up with a cherry on top.
那可当真是一团糟啊
Come on, let's get you sorted.
快来 给你打扮打扮
Welcome to the toy cupboard.
欢迎来到玩具专柜
I won't leave you my number.
我可不会把号码给你
You know Patch.
你知道帕奇
Patch Quartermain, the man himself.
帕奇·柯特蒙就是他
English.
英格力士
Please, don't get up.
不用起来
No chance of that.
想起也起不来
Lost them testing the B-6 exploding brogues.
测试B-6爆炸鞋时炸掉了
Oh, I'm so sorry. How are you?
很抱歉 还好吗
Have to be this one, I'm afraid.
只能握这只手了
Lost this to the D-10 doorbell.
D-10爆炸门铃把它炸了
Ah. Well, it's great to see what's left of you.
很高兴看到你还活着
This is rather good fun, actually. Top speed of 60 mph,
这轮椅很不错 最高时速六十英里
and I've managed to add the odd thing.
我还添了点小零件
This way. I haven't got all day.
这边 我可没时间耗
Don't!
别按
Would you stop meddling, English?
别瞎捣乱好吧 英格力士
Here she is.
她在这呢
Ah, the Rolls-Royce Phantom.
劳斯莱斯幻影
Truly the Rolls-Royce of automobiles.
应该说劳斯莱斯自动版
Armour plating, all the bells and whistles.
装甲钢板 还有好多小玩意儿
Say "Bonnet."
说句"发动"
- Bonnet. - Command accepted.
- 发动 - 命令接受
Voice activation recognises only you.
语音激活只识别你的声音
Rolls has fitted one of their experimental engines.
劳斯莱斯提供了一个实验引擎
The nine-litre V16. Goes like the wind.
九公升的V16 车速如风
Only quieter.
但却更安静
Beautiful.
漂亮
Keep up!
再看这儿
Here's what you'll be taking to Hong Kong.
这些是你去香港的装备
- Ah, yes. - A satellite receiver,
- 要来了 - 卫星接收器
tracking device, Semtex chewing gum.
跟踪装置 塑料炸弹口香糖
Now, what did I just say?
你刚才说什么
That's the new P-two digital dart gun.
那是新P2数字镖枪
Gentlemen. May I remind you all
先生们 友情提醒一下
that MI7's current weapon of choice is dialogue?
军情七处最新精配武器纯属扯淡
We do love it when you get strict, Pegasus.
我们最喜欢你严肃的样子 帕加索斯
English, you go to Hong Kong tonight.
英格力士 你今晚去香港
Fisher will contact you there.
费舍尔会联系你
To ensure protocol is observed,
为了确保按章办事
I'm sending someone with you.
我会派人跟着你
Agent Tucker.
特工塔克
It will be an honour, sir.
十分荣幸 长官
Well, it'll be good to have somebody to carry the bags.
有人帮忙提行李很不错
You made a laughing stock out of this service once, English.
你以前可闹出过笑话 英格力士
Not on my watch. Clear?
别给我添乱 明白吗
Crystal clear, Pegasus.
完全明白 帕加索斯
Just like old times, eh, Johnny?
和当年一样吧 约翰尼
I'm off to Switzerland. Let's catch up when you get back.
我要去瑞士 等你回来再说
There's nothing I'd like more, Simon.
乐意之至 西蒙
Has anyone seen the voice-changing travel lozenges?
有人看到变声旅游喉糖吗
No. No.
没 没
(香港)
(娱乐场)
(新葡京娱乐场 澳门)
谢谢
Come on, Tucker.
快点 塔克
I'm not 21 till September, sir. I'm not really allowed in.
九月我才满二十一岁 不可以进去
Tucker, you're an agent working for Her Majesty's Secret Service.
塔克 你可是女王特勤局的特工呀
Just act the part.
要像个特工的样子
Ten thousand dollars' worth, please, my lovely.
换一千美元筹码 宝贝
Thank you.
谢谢
And a receipt, please.
麻烦给张收据
Be alert for contact, Tucker.
注意找线人 塔克
We're looking for a Chinese man in spectacles.
要找戴眼镜的中国人
Would you like another drink, sir?
再来一杯吗 先生
Sir, the Chinese man in spectacles.
长官 戴眼镜的中国人
- One more beer. - No more bets, please.
- 再来一杯啤酒 - 买定离手
Contact.
线人
Evening.
晚上好
Your grandmother is sick.
你奶奶生病了
What?
什么
Your grandmother is sick.
你奶奶生病了
Well, she's dead. That's how sick she is.
她真病得不轻 死很久了
Is he dead, sir?
他死了吗
Yes.
是的
(九龙天堂 八号)
- Hi, Mum. - What's the matter?
- 嗨 妈妈 - 怎么了
No, no, no, no. Nothing's the matter, no.
没没没 没什么大事
I felt a bit funny last night, but I'm okay now.
昨晚有点不舒服 现在没事了
So, what have you got for us?
你手上有什么消息
The people behind the plot to kill Xiang Ping, the Chinese Premier.
幕后黑手要杀中国总理向平
A group called Vortex.
这个组织叫旋风组
Never heard of them.
没听过
Paid assassins. The best there is.
雇佣刺客 最好的
Come on, Fisher, I need names, I need evidence!
快点 费舍尔 我要的是名字 是证据
Vortex has a secret weapon.
旋风组有件秘密武器
This is one of three keys that,
拿到它需要集齐三把钥匙
when used together, gain access to it.
我手上有一把
Without this, Vortex is finished.
没了这钥匙 旋风组就完了
How did you get hold of it?
你是怎么得到的
It's mine.
这是我的
I beg your pardon?
什么
Vortex is three of us.
我们是旋风三人组
Come off it, Fisher.
别吹了 费舍尔
You, a hired assassin?
你 雇佣杀手吗
You couldn't hit a barn door with a banana.
就凭你那破枪法
And as for Vortex,
什么旋风
clearly you got the name off a box of washing powder.
这词肯定是从洗衣粉盒上看到的
Vortex was in Mozambique.
旋风组当时也在莫桑比克
What?
什么
Yeah? Really?
是 真的
Mum? Mum, Mum, I gotta go. Gotta go.
妈 妈妈 我得挂了 挂了
We were all there that day, Johnny-boy.
那一整天我们都在呢 小约翰尼
- Excuse me. Sir! - What?
- 打扰了 长官 - 什么
Sir, there's a...
长官 这...
Quick, come on! Come on!
快点 快 快
Madam, let me help you with that.
女士 我来帮你提
Here. Yes, I think you should vacate the area.
来 对 我想你该离开这里
There are some very dangerous people about.
这里有危险人物
There we go.
好了
Get after her, Tucker, get after her!
抓住她 塔克 抓住她
What?
什么
Sir! Sir!
长官 长官
Over here, Tucker!
这里 塔克
I lost her, sir.
跟丢了 长官
Look what I found.
看我找到了什么
This way, sir! This way!
这里 长官 这里
You get down to the street. I'll take the roof.
你到街上去 我到楼顶去
You are not young. But with age comes wisdom.
你虽青春不再 但姜还是老的辣
Hand it over, chimp.
交出来 猩猩
(三号电梯)
Come on, Tucker.
快点 塔克
Can I help?
需要我帮忙吗
I am commandeering this vessel in the name of Her Majesty.
我以女王的名义征用这艘船
Right-O, Wing Commander.
遵命 中校
How exciting!
太刺激了
Now, what's your poison? Can I get you something?
喜欢喝点什么 我给您拿
We've got vodka, rum.
有伏特加和朗姆酒
Your safety is our priority.
您的安全是我们的首要任务
But you can help us by familiarizing yourself with this leaflet.
想更好地配合我们的工作 请看这份传单
Creme de menthe, a smidgen of port,
薄荷甜酒 一点波尔图葡萄酒
and that's about it, I'm afraid.
我想这不错
I'm Shirley.
我是雪莉
Hello, Shirley.
你好 雪莉
Just a tad to your left, Shirley. Thank you.
往左一点 雪莉 谢谢
I say, Wing Commander!
干得好 中校
站起来
你碰到火柴棒了
- Well played, sir! Well played! - Just like a gladiator!
- 漂亮 长官 - 就像角斗士
Come on. Put 'em up.
快点 打吧
Well played, sir! Well played!
干得好 长官
More champagne, my lovely.
再来点香槟 宝贝
Certainly, sir.
当然 长官
Tucker are you sure you don't want a Shandy or something?
塔克 你确定不来点香蒂酒之类吗
I have got to finish this mission report, sir.
我得完成任务报告呢 长官
And Pegasus wants to see us as soon as we touchdown.
我们一着陆 帕加索斯就要见我们
The mission report?
任务报告
Oh, come on, Tucker. Live a little.
别写了 塔克 人生苦短啊
You should learn to savour success.
得学会品尝胜利
Work hard,
努力工作
play hard. Isn't that right...
痛快玩乐 不是吗...
Barbara?
芭芭拉
Vortex is finished.
旋风组完蛋了
But better still,
但至少
for years
多年来
I believed what happened in Mozambique was my fault.
我一直觉得莫桑比克的事是我的过错
Now I realise it was only partly my fault.
现在我知道不全是这样
What did happen in Mozambique?
在莫桑比克到底发生了什么
Excuse me, sir. We're coming in to land.
打扰了 先生 就要着陆了
Can I stow that overhead for you?
我帮您放到架子上好吗
Certainly.
当然
Sir, I don't think he's a "Susan."
长官 我不觉得他会叫"苏珊"
But then you're not a linguist, are you, Tucker?
你不是语言学家吧 塔克
It's not "Susan," its "Shoooshan."
不是"苏珊" 是"书山"
From the Xinzhou region,
来自忻州地区
unless I'm very much mistaken.
除非是我大错特错
Thank you, Shoooshan.
谢谢 书山
Foreign Secretary.
外交部长先生
I hope you've got something for us, English.
希望你有所收获 英格力士
The Prime Minister is extremely concerned.
首相对此极为关心
He has every reason to be so.
必须的
There is a plot to kill the Chinese Premier.
有人密谋杀害中国总理
Masterminded by a group of ruthless assassins called Vortex.
策划者是一群残忍的杀手组成的旋风组
Good Lord.
天啊
The danger, however, has been averted.
警报已经解除了
Now that we have this.
因为我们得到了这个
English?
英格力士
Now, I know what you're going to say,
我知道你要说什么
it's a pretty small object.
这东西很小巧是吧
Well, it's often the little things that pack the biggest punch.
世事往往是四两拨千斤
- After all, David killed Goliath with a pebble. - Sir.
- 正如大卫用卵石杀了哥利亚 - 长官
The mighty Vortex has been slain by
当我拥有了这把小巧钥匙时
my possession of this small key.
强大的旋风组已经被扼杀了
Shoooshan.
书山
Susan.
是苏珊
We got it, but Fisher talked.
拿到钥匙了 可费舍尔泄密了
Understood. We'll deal with English.
明白 我们会干掉英格力士
You've got some more cleaning to do.
你还得再打扫一下
Mummy, Mummy! Mr. Rhubarb's here!
妈妈 妈妈 大黄先生在这
Izzie, darling,
伊兹 亲爱的
why don't you show him into the conservatory?
为什么不把他带暖房里去
I'll be with you in just a minute.
我等会就来陪你
Okay. Come on, come on, let's go!
好的 快点 快走
- Shall we? - Hurry up, Mr. Rhubarb.
- 走吗 - 快点 大黄先生
Perhaps when you've found your key, you'll give me a call.
等你找你的钥匙 给我打个电话
I'm very sorry, Foreign Secretary.
很抱歉 外长先生
I had hoped to have more for you.
本来想能给您带来更多好信息
Oh, God.
天啊
Pegasus! I've got her!
帕加索斯 我抓到她了
Come on, you witch.
过来 你个女巫
English?
英格力士
She was in Hong Kong! She's the killer!
她就是在香港的那个杀手
She's my mother!
她是我妈妈
Couldn't she be both?
会不会是双面娇娃
Mummy, Mummy, are you all right?
妈妈 妈妈 你没事吧
Let me get you a cup of tea.
我给你倒杯茶
- You'll be fine, Mummy. - Who was that man?
- 你会没事的 妈妈 - 那人是谁
Yeah, I think a cup of tea, that's what's required.
按她说的 上杯茶吧
Pegasus, I am truly, truly sorry.
帕加索斯 真的真的很抱歉
Don't apologise to me. Apologise to her.
别跟我道歉 跟她说去
I cannot apologise enough, Mrs. Pegasus.
再抱歉不过了 帕加索斯太太
It was a simple case of mistaken identity, I'm afraid.
我想我弄错身份了
Now, I completely understand
现在 我完全明白
how upset you are, but I was hoping perhaps...
你很难受 但我希望也许你...
Sir!
长官
Tucker! That's her! It's the killer from Hong Kong!
塔克 是她 香港的杀手
- No, it's not her, sir. - It is! This time it's really her!
- 不 不是她 长官 - 是她 绝对
- It's not her, sir! - Yes, it is!
- 不是 长官 - 绝对是
Make way!
让开
Sir.
长官
You murderous crone!
你这个残忍的老母羊
Granny! What's he doing?
奶奶 他在干嘛
Take that! And that!
我打 我打
Hey! Stop it.
快停下
English!
英格力士
I've got her this time, Pegasus!
这次抓住她了 帕加索斯
This is the witch who works for Vortex!
她就是为旋风组服务的女巫
Want any more you old hag?
还没打够吗
- English! - Granny!
- 英格力士 - 奶奶
You humiliate me in front of the Foreign Secretary,
你在外交部长面前羞辱我
you lose our only lead on Vortex,
弄丢了旋风组唯一的线索
and then you try and kill my mother!
现在还想杀我妈妈
Twice!
两次
Pegasus, we have another lead.
帕加索斯 我们另有线索
Vortex was in Mozambique!
旋风组在莫桑比克
They were responsible for the death of President Chambal!
他们应该对昌巴尔总统的死负责
No! You were responsible for the death of President Chambal.
不 你才该对昌巴尔总统的死负责
Well, you certainly gave Mr.Rhubarb a run for his money.
你完全抢了小丑先生的风头
Still, at least we know Vortex was in Mozambique.
不过 至少我们知道旋风组当时就在莫桑比克
When you told Pegasus,
当你告诉帕加索斯的时候
you displayed all four indicators of someone telling the truth.
表现出了说实话的四大特征
This is a facial action coding system.
这是个面部动作编码系统
Its high-speed cameras record microexpressions
它的高速摄像镜头可以捕捉到
invisible to the naked eye.
肉眼看不到的微表情
It detects what we call emotional leakage.
探察到所谓的情感泄露
Ms.Sumner, I'm a trained agent. I don't "Leak."
萨姆纳女士 我是训练有素的特工 决不泄密
I want to take you back to Mozambique.
我想让你重返莫桑比克
Is that really necessary?
有这个必要吗
Take a look at this.
来看看这个
I want to take you back to Mozambique.
我想让你重返莫桑比克
There.
看到了吧
Could we call that leakage?
这算不算泄密呢
Now, play ball.
好了 开工吧
I'm taking a risk being here after hours.
非工作时间来这 我可是冒了险
If Vortex was in Mozambique,
如果旋风组当时在莫桑比克
perhaps you saw something.
你可能看到些什么
I'm going to take you back there using hypnosis.
我会通过催眠让你回到当时的场景
Oh, please.
饶了我吧
Spare me the new age mumbo jumbo.
你可以省了这些时髦把戏
Mr.English, please. I'm a professional.
英格力士先生 拜托 我是专业人士
I'm not going to just snap my fingers
我不会随便打个响指
and make you say the first thing that comes into your head.
让你说出映入脑海的第一件事物
Plump pillows.
蓬松的枕头
Excuse me?
你说什么
Brilliant mind. Beautiful face.
聪慧的头脑 美丽的面庞
Incredible.
不会吧
And completely out of my league.
我完全攀不上的美女
I'd like to take you back to Mozambique.
我现在要你回到莫桑比克
Tell me what's happening, Johnny. Where are you?
说说你看到了什么 约翰尼 你在哪里
President Chambal's inauguration day.
昌巴尔总统的就职大典
Yes, you're head of security.
没错 你是安保负责人
Everything's going perfectly.
一切都相当顺利
Today we climb the mountain!
今天 我们勇攀高峰
Agent English.
英格力士特工
The people have spoken, and the message is clear.
群众的呼声 我都听到了
A future of peace and prosperity!
一个崭新的和平繁荣之邦
The backup electrical supply has been cut.
备用电源被切断了
No, it hasn't. It's been turned off.
没有切断 只是被关上了
Do you know how to turn it on?
那你知道 怎么打开你的开关吗
I should be getting back.
我该回去了
Well, operations like this are always difficult.
这种任务总是相当棘手
But it's very satisfying when you get a result.
不过圆满完成后 我还是深感欣慰
The President couldn't be in safer hands.
保护总统 舍我其谁
The future belongs to Mozambique!
未来属于莫桑比克
Thank you.
谢谢
The fireworks have begun.
开始放礼花了吧
The sound of freedom and celebration.
庆祝自由与欢呼喝彩之音
Easy, Johnny. Easy. Go back.
别紧张 约翰尼 放松 回想一下
Before the Jacuzzi, what did you see?
在洗按摩浴之前 你还看到了什么
Yes.
是的
Fisher.
费舍尔
On the terrace with two others.
和另外两个人在露台上
Yes. All three members of Vortex were there that day.
是的 旋风组的三名成员那天都在场
Who can you see? Who can you see, Johnny?
你看到谁了 都有谁 约翰尼
Artem Karlenko.
阿提姆·卡尔兰科
Artem Karlenko, double agent.
阿提姆·卡尔兰科 双重间谍
Recruited by MI7 in Moscow.
曾受雇于莫斯科的军情七处
Retired after his penchant for killing people
对于可能暴露他身份的人都格杀勿论
threatened his cover.
因此被遣退
Five years ago, he turned up here,
五年前 他在这里现身
as Sergei Pudovkin.
化名谢尔盖·普多夫金
Rich, very rich.
他是个富豪 很有钱
A member of the exclusive Oakwood Golf Club,
是奥克伍德顶级高尔夫俱乐部的会员
which is where you'll be meeting him.
你就在那儿跟他见面
He's in a match play competition, sir.
他在那里参加比洞赛 长官
I'm making you his opponent for the day.
我会把你设为他今天的比赛对手
(比洞赛 上午10点30分, 彼特·亚当斯对战谢尔盖·普多夫金)
Done it, sir. You're booked in as Mr.Peter Adams.
搞定 你将化身彼特·亚当斯先生参加比赛
Thank you, Tucker.
谢了 塔克
If Karlenko is Vortex,
如果卡尔兰科是旋风组的一员
I want you to bring him in. Alive.
把他给我带回来 要活的
Mr.Pussykin?
是普丝巾先生吗
Pudovkin. And you must be Mr. ...
是普多夫金 那你一定就是
Adams.
亚当斯
Beautiful car, Mr.Adams.
车很棒 亚当斯先生
Ah, the Royce.
我的劳斯莱斯
Ready, sir.
准备就绪 长官
Thank you.
多谢夸奖
Shall we?
走吗
Let's go.
出发吧
Command accepted.
命令接受
So, what line of business are you in, Mr.Adams?
那你从事什么行业呢 亚当斯先生
Pudovkin.
我叫普多夫金
Sorry. Yes, I'm Mr Adams, and you're Mr...
抱歉 没错 我才叫亚当斯 你叫
Whoever you said you were.
你说的那个什么名字
- Well... - Stop!
- 好吧 - 停下
Sorry, I thought I had forgotten something.
不好意思 我以为自己忘了东西
Glove, sir?
戴手套吧 先生
I may not know much about golf, Tucker,
塔克 虽然我不是打高尔夫的行家
but I know how to hold the bat.
可还是能握好球杆
Shot, sir.
好球 先生
So, what line of business are you in, Mr.Puddykin?
你做哪一行生意呢 普地精先生
I made my money in the removals business.
我是做拆迁生意的
A friend of mine had shares in a removals business.
我有个朋友也做拆迁买卖
Titus Fisher.
他叫提图斯·费舍尔
You haven't come across him at all?
你跟他有来往吗
I warn you, Mr.Adams, not to stray into the rough.
我可警告你 亚当斯先生 别趟这浑水
You get in there, you might never come out.
因为一旦陷进去 可能就出不来了
I'll bear that in mind, Mr.Puddykin.
谨记在心 普地精先生
Pudovkin. Please.
劳驾 我叫普多夫金
Shot!
进了
As was my friend Fisher, actually,
事实上 就跟我的朋友费舍尔一样
in the back,
子弹从身后穿进
by his cleaner, of all people.
偏偏还是他的清洁工干的
But they didn't take much.
不过他们也没抢什么
Just a key.
就拿了把钥匙
Break, left to right, I think.
赛点 我觉得可以从左往右打
Thank you.
多谢
干掉他
In the trees.
在树林那边
Come on.
快来
- Oh, my god. - He can't die. He mustn't die.
- 天啊 - 他不能死 绝对不能
Let's get him out of here. Come on! Come on.
带他离开这儿 快点
He's not looking good, sir.
长官 他看起来不妙
We're getting you to a doctor. You'll be fine.
我们带你去医院 你会没事的
You do know how to fly this, sir?
你会开这玩意儿吧 长官
- It was part of basic training. - Good.
- 这是基础训练之一 - 太好了
It's just like riding a bike.
跟骑自行车没两样
Yes. It's all coming back to me.
对 我全记起来了
This is helicopter Golf Hotel Zulu Zulu Tango.
这里是祖鲁祖鲁探戈高尔夫酒店的直升机
We have a casualty on board.
机上有一位伤员
Request guidance to nearest hospital.
请指示最近的医院地址
Where's your exact location?
请说你们的具体位置
Our location? Location?
位置 我们的位置
She shot out the navigation system.
她打坏了导航系统
Hang on.
抓紧了
- Runstock. - Our location is Runstock.
- 兰斯多克 - 我们在兰斯多克
What is your altitude?
飞行高度是多少
What's our altitude?
飞行高度吗
About 18 inches.
大约18英寸
Hello? Hello?
喂 喂
Sorry. I'll just move.
抱歉 马上开走
What now, sir?
现在怎么办 长官
We'll have to stick to the road. Let's follow the 1328.
我们得沿着路开 就走1328道吧
There's bound to be a hospital in Dingham.
鼎汉一定有医院
(鼎汉)
Look after him, Tucker. Look after him.
看看他 塔克 去看看他
I think we're losing him, sir.
我觉得他不行了 长官
We can't lose him, Tucker.
不行也得行 塔克
He's our only lead. Try something else.
他是我们唯一的线索 再想别的辙
Don't give up on us, baby
不要就此放弃 宝贝
Lord knows we've come this far
上帝知道一路走来的疲惫
We are the angel and the dreamer
我们都是 天使和梦想家
Don't give up on us, I know
不要就此放弃 我相信
We could still come through
我们定会战胜困难与艰辛
Look, sir! Follow that ambulance!
看啊 长官 跟着那辆急救车
Good idea.
好主意
Sir. Sir, quickly.
长官 长官 快点
Karlenko. Karlenko!
卡尔兰科 卡尔兰科
The second key.
这是第二把钥匙
Vortex is KGB...
旋风组的成员 一个是克格勃的
- Yes. - CIA.
- 是 - 一个是中情局的
Yes? Yes?
是 还有呢
MI7.
一个是军情七处的
Unbelievable. A vole in MI7.
难以置信 军情七处竟然有内魂
A mole, sir.
应该是内鬼 长官
What?
什么
There's a mole in MI7.
军情七处有个内鬼
There's a mole and a vole?
有个内魂还有个内鬼吗
No, sir. There's a mole, not a vole.
不是的 长官 有一个内鬼 不是内魂
Well, I disagree. There's certainly a vole.
我不同意 肯定有个内魂
I mean, we know that much.
证据确凿 毋庸置疑
But what you're saying is there might be a mole as well.
但你刚刚说可能还有个内鬼
Pegasus.
是帕加索斯
There's a meeting at MI7 with the Prime Minister.
首相要来军情七处开会
(军情七处总部 1012室 17点45分)
And here again, eyes down and to the left, indicating dissent.
再看这里 眼神向下再向左 表示不同意
With Xiang Ping, it's all about the eyes.
通过向平的眼睛 便知道他的内心活动
Thank you, Ms.Sumner.
谢谢 萨姆纳女士
If the talks go ahead, I'd like you with us.
如果会晤继续的话 希望你也能出席
Yes, Prime Minister.
好的 首相大人
Good evening, gentlemen.
先生们 晚上好
- Mr.English. - Ms.Sumner.
- 你好 英格力士先生 - 你好 萨姆纳女士
Right.
好了
So when is the Prime Minister
那咱们的首相大人
going to grace us with his presence?
要何时大驾光临呢
I'm the Prime Minister.
我就是首相
Yeah, you wish.
就你 少做梦了
All right. So we're all here.
好吧 那么人齐了
These talks with China are of paramount importance.
这次与中国首脑的会晤非常重要
Rogue states in Southeast Asia
东南亚那些蛮夷
have begun secretly to develop nuclear weapons.
已经在秘密开发核武
It is vital that we get China onside.
所以 与中国达成共识很关键
Traditionally, China has been impervious to our concerns,
一般而言 中国不会支持我们的观点
but I believe Xiang Ping, given the opportunity,
但我相信 要是时机恰当
can and will help defuse this situation.
向平有能力并愿意协助我们解除危机
Well, with his pro-West stance,
鉴于他对西方的友好态度
it certainly offers an opportunity,
我们还是有机会的
but the talks can't go ahead unless we can guarantee his safety.
但要保证他的安全 这次会晤才能继续
I believe, with the correct security, that we can.
我认为 安保得当就没问题
If Vortex is operational, it's just too dangerous.
如果旋风组在密谋行动 那就很危险了
I'm inclined to agree, Prime Minister.
我也同意 首相
There is a way.
我有个办法
The Swiss are willing to lend us Le Bastion.
瑞士政府同意把空中堡垒借给我们
That's their government fortress in the Alps.
那是他们在阿尔卑斯山脉的军事要塞
It's a stunning example of architectural engineering at altitude,
一座非常优秀的高地工事
and completely impregnable.
可谓坚不可摧
I mean, that should solve all our security issues.
这样就能解决我们的安全问题
Then the talks go ahead.
那么会晤将继续进行
Pamela, I hope you've brushed up on your Mandarin.
帕姆拉 我希望你多温习普通话
I'd like you in the room with me, and
到时你和这里最好的特工
your best man on security.
会紧随我左右
Yes, Prime Minister.
好的 首相大人
Where are we on Vortex?
旋风组这边调查的怎么样了
English?
英格力士
Vortex is three men.
旋风组是个三人组
Fisher was one, Karlenko was another.
一个是费舍尔 一个是卡尔兰科
Karlenko was killed today on the orders of the third.
而卡尔兰科今天被那第三个人杀害了
Any leads?
有什么线索吗
Yes, but I need time.
有 但需要时间调查
We do not have time.
没时间了
We need to know the identity of the third person in Vortex.
我们需要知道旋风组第三名成员的身份
Give me 24 hours.
给我一天的时间
Another bottle of Romainee-Conti?
再来一瓶罗曼尼康帝
Of course. And would you like to choose dessert?
没问题 您需要什么甜点吗
Yes. You.
是的 就点你这甜心
And bring two spoons.
那我也要分杯羹
- Cheers. - Cheers.
- 干杯 - 干杯
So, come on, Johnny, what was it you wanted to ask me?
说吧 约翰尼 你想问我什么
Simon, do you know what this is?
西蒙 你认识这个吗
Some sort of key?
有点像把钥匙
Karlenko and Fisher both had one,
卡尔兰科和费舍尔各有一把
and they were both killed for them.
也都因此而被杀害了
Well, I'll give it to the boys at the lab and see...
那我拿去给实验室的哥们看看再...
Karlenko told me that the third man in Vortex is in MI7.
卡尔兰科告诉我 第三个人就在军情七处里
And you believed him?
那你相信他说的吗
Simon, I have to ask you a question, face to face.
西蒙 我必须要当着你的面问清楚
Do you have any idea who it might be?
你觉得这个人会是谁呢
Johnny, I thought you were about to accuse me.
约翰尼 我还以为你在怀疑我呢
No! I mean, honestly.
怎么会 当然没有
- What? - Simon Ambrose, the evil mastermind!
- 什么 - 西蒙·安布罗斯 邪恶的大反派
- Don't. Stop it. - The traitor in our midst!
- 快别说了 - 我们中的大叛徒
You! You!
你啊 你啊
Simon, you are so funny.
西蒙 你太幽默了
Hysterical.
快笑抽了
Oh, dear.
天啊
(塔克: 快来洗手间 十万火急)
Would you excuse me for one moment, Simon?
不好意思 失陪一下 西蒙
- Sir. - Tucker, can't this wait?
- 长官 - 塔克 你就不能等等吗
Sir, it's Ambrose.
长官 是安布罗斯
Yes, I know it's Ambrose. I'm having dinner with him.
是啊 我知道是安布罗斯 我正和他吃饭呢
No, he's the third man in Vortex.
不是 他就是旋风组的第三个人
Simon Ambrose?
西蒙·安布罗斯吗
He went to Eton.
他可是伊顿公学的高材生
Simon.
西蒙
Leave it.
别动
- What are you... - Move.
- 你这是干什 - 过去
- All right, all right. - Come on, move.
- 好 好 - 快点 过去
Tucker.
塔克
- You said you never knew Karlenko. - That's right.
- 你说你根本不认识卡尔兰科 - 没错
Then how do you explain these?
那你如何解释这张照片
I hacked into Karlenko's computer.
我潜入了卡尔兰科的计算机
You and him in Mozambique?
这是你们俩在莫桑比克吧
Sometimes I have trouble myself, old boy.
我有时也不能淋漓尽致 老兄
You're Vortex! You're the third man in Vortex!
你就是旋风组的 你是旋风组的第三个人
Tucker, this is ridiculous.
塔克 这太荒谬了
Sorry, I'll be with you in just a tick.
抱歉 我马上解决
It's true, I was in Mozambique.
没错 我当时在莫桑比克
What?
你说什么
I was there because of Patch Quartermain.
但我是因为帕奇·柯特蒙才去的
Patch? Sorry, I'll just be one second.
帕奇吗 抱歉 马上就好
He's the man you're after.
他才是你要抓的人
- You're bluffing! - Sorry.
- 少糊弄我 - 不好意思
I work for a secret organisation inside MI7
军情七处为了逮捕他专门建了个秘密组织
set up specifically to bring him in.
我就是其中一员
A secret Secret Service?
秘密组织里的秘密组织吗
Yeah? What's it called?
是吗 那这个组织叫什么
What's it called?
到底叫什么
(阿米蒂奇·香克斯)
Armitage.
阿米蒂奇
A secret secret secret service called Armitage?
一个叫阿米蒂奇的秘密的秘密的秘密行动组织
We answer only to the PM.
我们直接听命于首相
It's extraordinary, Simon...
太离奇了吧 西蒙
Indeed, it is.
事实就是如此
...That you'd think for one moment
你难道真的认为
that I would fall for such a steaming pile of old baloney.
我会相信你这套不靠谱的胡诌乱扯吗
Well done, Tucker.
干得漂亮 塔克
You're not Spy of the Month for nothing.
果真是本月特工之星
- Thank you, sir. - Here, let me take that.
- 谢谢夸奖 长官 - 来 把枪给我
Now go home.
好了 回家吧
- What? - You're the one talking baloney.
- 什么 - 你才是胡诌乱扯的那个
You're in way over your head, boy. Now run along.
你脑子里真是团浆糊 孩子 快走吧
No! I won't go, sir. He's lying.
不 我不走 长官 他在撒谎
You've let me down, you've let the Service down,
我对你很失望 军情处对你很失望
and, frankly, I think you've let yourself down.
说实话 你也应该对自己感到失望
- But I... - Now get out!
- 但我 - 快给我离开
Patch Quartermain, of all people.
帕奇·柯特蒙 怎么会是他呢
Blowing his own legs off?
他炸掉了自己的双腿吗
Now that's what I call deep cover.
这就是我说的深藏不露
And to think how much I admired him.
想想我之前多佩服他
He hates you.
他讨厌你
- Really? - He always has.
- 真的吗 - 一直都是
He thinks you're a moron with no place in MI7,
他觉得你就是个自大的无名小卒
a jumped-up grammar school nobody.
蠢蛋一只 根本不配待在军情七处
That's why he tried to destroy you.
所以他才设计陷害你
Now, Johnny, just because he ruined your life,
听着 约翰尼 千万不要因为他毁了你的生活
that's no reason for you
你就失去理智
to go rogue and take him down on your own.
单枪匹马地去找他算账
God forbid I should put a crazy idea like that in your head.
我真不应该跟你说这番话
Good night, Simon.
晚安 西蒙
Johnny,
约翰尼
that key you showed me. We might need it to bring him in.
我们可能要拿刚才那把钥匙去逮捕他
- Thank you. - You're welcome, sir.
- 谢谢 - 不客气 长官
Silly tit.
傻帽
Bingo.
搞定
- Arrange a meeting with our client - Of course.
- 给我们和客户安排一个会议 - 好的
Pegasus.
帕加索斯
We have the third man.
知道第三个人是谁了
It's Johnny English.
就是约翰尼·英格力士
Hello, Patch.
你好 帕奇
Looking for forgiveness?
在请求宽恕吗
It's all over for you now, English. It's the end of the line.
都结束了 英格力士 你走投无路了
Yes, you'd like that, wouldn't you, Patch?
是啊 你当然想 是不是 帕奇
After all, I'm just a jumped-up grammar school nobody, aren't I?
毕竟我就是个自大的无名小卒而已
What are you talking about?
你在说什么呢
I know that you are the third man in Vortex.
我知道你就是旋风组的第三名成员
No, Johnny. You are.
不对 约翰尼 你是
No, you are.
不 你是
No. You are!
不 你才是
Standby, all agents.
所有特工就位
And it all ends here.
一切都到此为止了
Take him.
抓住他
Johnny.
约翰尼
(车速: 快)
Hey! Watch it!
干吗呢 看着点
Got him!
找到他了
Move! Move!
借过 借过
Don't lose him. Go, go!
别让他跑了 快点快点
Halt!
停
Heading west into Vine Street. Mobilise all vehicles.
向西驶入怀恩大街 调动一切车辆
(车速: 飞快)
Idiot!
神经病
You've lost him! I don't believe it.
这都能跟丢 难以置信
Oi! Who do you think you are?
嘿 你以为你是谁啊
Gotcha.
让你跑
(车速: 飞快)
Agent English, pull over! Pullover!
特工英格力士 停车 快停车
(车速: 极快)
(睡眠模式)
Stop it!
停车
Get after him.
追
Kate, Kate,
凯特 凯特
I'm not Vortex. I've been framed.
我不是旋风组的 我被陷害了
You must believe me.
你得相信我
How will it be done?
打算如何行动
Same as in Mozambique.
跟莫桑比克的一样
One person, apparently working alone.
单人行动
Who have you chosen?
人你选好了吗
Leave that with me.
我会决定的
My account in Zurich.
我在苏黎世的账户
500 million US dollars, as agreed.
五亿美元 按规矩
You've been out for hours
你晕过去好半天
Well, you're lucky it was just a flesh wound.
所幸只是皮肉伤
Now, look, I'm going to Switzerland tonight,
听着 我今晚要去瑞士
but you can stay here while I'm gone.
我走了你可以待在这
I've been going through the
我在查看
news footage from the night Chambal was killed.
昌巴尔遇刺那晚的监控录像
And there's something not right.
有点蹊跷
Seconds after President Chambal was shot,
昌巴尔总统被刺之后的片刻
the assassin collapses and dies.
刺客突然倒地而死
And the autopsy says heart failure.
尸检报告是心脏停跳
But, if you go through the classified CCTV footage...
但如果你看一下内部闭路电视画面
You all right?
没事吧你
Yeah, fine.
很好啊
Take a look at this.
来看看
Fifteen minutes before the assassination, look,
行刺的十五分钟前
he's manic.
他开始狂躁
He's completely lost control of his body
他完全控制不了自己的身体
And then, suddenly, catatonic.
然后 突然像是紧张性神经分裂症
Here, wait.
这里 等等
There.
就这里
Someone was talking to him.
有人跟他说话
I don't think he had any idea what he was doing.
我觉得他压根不知道自己在做什么
I think Vortex's secret weapon...
我想旋风组组织的秘密武器
Is a mind control drug.
就是一种能控制思维的药
And only one fits the symptoms.
只有一种药符合以上症状
Timox... Timoxylin Bubby...
地莫克西... 地莫克西林巴巴
Timoxeline Barbebutenol.
地莫克西林巴伯布特纳
The CIA ordered its destruction 10 years ago.
中情局十年前命令将其销毁
And the agent in charge of its disposal...
负责处置它的特工是
Titus Fisher.
提图斯·费舍尔
I don't know how to thank you.
我对你无以为报
I'd love a take-away.
共进晚餐吧
Consider it done.
就这么定了
Flying low.
小门开了
So, Johnny, what are you going to do about Vortex?
约翰尼 你打算怎么对付旋风组组织
I don't know. If only Simon was here. He'd know what to do.
不知道啊 如果西蒙在就有办法了
Why do you think he's better than you?
你为什么觉着他比你强
Well, the man's a god.
他是个神人啊
Well, I prefer mortals.
我更喜欢凡人
Pure, complicated, maddening mortals.
单纯又难以捉摸 让人疯狂的凡人
I've come to realise that what's really exciting to me
我才发现最让我心潮澎湃的
is great loyalty, determination,
是绝对的忠诚 决心
and courage.
和勇气
You have always fascinated me, clinically.
你总是让我神魂颠倒 正中下怀
But now you...
而你现在
Ms Sumner, your pupils are dilating.
萨姆纳小姐 你瞳孔在扩大
Are they?
有吗
Your cheeks are colouring.
你两颊开始红润
Eye contact deepening.
秋波频送
Heart-rate rising.
心率加速
Ms Sumner, I believe we're emotionally leaking.
萨姆纳小姐 我觉着理性已经阻止不了我们了
- The bedroom, quickly. - Absolutely.
- 快去屋里 - 遵命
Now!
赶紧啊
- Hello? - Hello.
- 谁 - 我
- Oh, Simon. - Hi, Kate.
- 西蒙是你啊 - 凯特
You ready? I'll drive you to the airport.
准备好了吗 我送你去机场
How nice. I'll just get my bag.
真贴心 我去拿包
You alone?
你自己吗
No. Of course.
别 当然
Been working?
在工作呢
Been brushing up on the Chinese PM. You?
准备一下中国总理的资料 你呢
We're trying to track clown Johnny English
我们在追查约翰尼·英格力士
There's some questions we want to ask him, about Vortex.
关于旋风组我们有些事想问他
I don't suppose you've seen him, have you?
我猜你没看见他吧 对吗
No.
对啊
Not hiding him away?
没把他藏起来
Not my type. Shall we?
像我做出来的事吗 走吧
Ambrose.
安布罗斯
There's a Mr Adams to see you, Colin.
科林 有个亚当斯先生要见你
- Hello, Tucker. - What are you doing here?
- 塔克 - 你在这儿干嘛
Every agent in the country is after you.
你正被全国通缉
We were right about Ambrose
我们猜安布罗斯是对的
What do you mean "we"?
什么叫我们啊
And if we can act fast, we can still...
如果咱够快 还能...
You wouldn't listen, would you?
你能听句劝吗
You think you know it all. Well' you don't!
你自以为什么都知道 狗屁
Being an agent means everything to me.
当特工是我毕生梦想
And, thanks to you, I'm suspended!
多亏你 我被停职了
Would you boys like some orange squash?
你们谁来点橙汁吗
- No, thank you. - Bye, thanks, Mum.
- 不用 谢谢谢 - 免了 老妈
Tucker, Ambrose is in Switzerland.
小兄弟 安布罗斯在瑞士
We are in duty.
我们责无旁贷
I am here because my country needs me.
我来这儿 是因为国家需要我
And because it needs you, too.
她也需要你
- Royce. - Ready, sir.
- 劳斯莱斯 - 准备就绪 长官
Come.
过来
Obstruction detected.
测得前方障碍
Set the sat nav for Switzerland Let's kick some bottom.
导航系统锁定瑞士 咱们起飞
(时速216公里 违章)
You have arrived at your destination.
已经到达终点
Good luck, sir!
祝你好运 长官
Le Bastion.
空中堡垒
One way up, one way down.
上下各只有一条路
Come on. Let's get the stuff.
来吧 准备一下
Whoa, look. The T-2 ground-to-air missile!
看啊 T-2地对空导弹
That's a D-7 bulletproof shield.
这是D-7防弹伞
Take it from me, Tucker.
好好学学 塔克
I was working with these while you were stringing conkers.
我玩这些的时候你还不知道在哪儿捏泥巴呢
The P-8 grapple hook?
P-8倒抓钩
Check.
好了
- Estimated height? - Thirty-five feet.
- 目测高度 - 十一米
All yours, Tucker.
交给你了
Can I just say, sir?
我能说一句吗
This is just great.
真棒极了
Well, go on.
来吧
The D-16 ascender, and up we go.
D-16攀爬器 看好了
Are you sure that's the ascender, sir?
你确定这是攀爬器吗
Yes, yes, I'd know it anywhere.
闭着眼睛都知道
Agent in distress. Agent in distress.
特工被困 特工被困
特工受困 特工受困
I am over here!
我在这里
Shut up! Shut up!
闭嘴 闭嘴
I am over here!
我在这里
Activating visual locater.
发射信号弹
Three, two, one.
三 二 一
在那边
Intruders in Sector Four!
四区有人闯入
Dear God, let me not die at the hands of the Swiss.
我的天哪 别让我死在瑞士佬手里
Tucker, now listen. I want you to attack me
塔克 听着 你来打我
- What? - After a struggle,
- 啥 - 一番争斗之后
you can "Arrest me". And take me inside as your prisoner.
你可以逮捕我 然后把我押进堡垒里
- Sir, I can't. - Tucker, that's an order.
- 不行 - 这是命令
Hit me. Hit me.
打我啊 打我
Come on, harder.
使劲儿
- Better, sh'? - Yes, much better.
- 好点不 - 好多了
I can see how people get a taste for this.
看来还真有人有这癖好
I got a better idea. I'll shoot you!
我有个更好的主意 我朝你开枪
No, no, no.
不不不
- Die, Vortex scum! - Tucker!
- 去死吧 旋风组的人渣 - 塔克
Agent Tucker!
特工塔克
It's Johnny English.
这是约翰尼·英格力士
Bag him.
装袋带走
The glass can withstand mortar attack.
这玻璃连炮都轰不开
The door's one-way.
门能从里面反锁
You can get out, but no one gets in.
你能出来但没人进得去
Excellent.
好极了
You ready, Slater?
斯莱特 好了吗
I'll have them send refreshments to your room
帕加索斯 你准备好了
when you're ready, Pegasus.
我就让他们把饮料给你送进去
Thank you, Agent One.
谢谢你 特工一号
I'll take it from here, boys.
弟兄们 我来接手吧
Hold it right there!
站那儿别动
Let me see your ID.
出示一下你的身份
- Excuse me - What the...
- 不好意思 - 这是什...
Stop!
停
Warning, this is a designated conflict zone.
看好了 这里是格斗区
Sir? Sir?
长官 长官
Thank you so much
非常感谢
You're welcome, Pegasus.
不客气 帕加索斯
Pegasus.
帕加索斯
Go on. Go on.
快喝 快喝
What the hell is that?
那是什么鬼东西
Sir? Sir?
长官 长官
- English! - Pegasus.
- 英格力士 - 帕加索斯
They're going to make you kill Xiang Ping!
他们想让你行刺向平
You're insane!
你疯了
Agent One, thank God.
一号特工 谢天谢地
He won't help you.
他不是来帮你的
He's the third member of Vortex.
他是旋风组的第三号
Aren't you, Simon?
对吧 西蒙
Here to give you some Timoxy bubby...
他来是给你地莫克西...巴巴...
Timoxy bubby...
地莫克西巴巴...
地莫克西巴贝...
To give you a drug
给你一种药
that will make you obey his every command.
让你服从他的命令
I'm intrigued, Simon.
我倒很想看看 西蒙
How exactly were you going to administer it?
你打算怎么实施呢
By injection?
皮下注射
Some hideous gas through the air vents?
从通风口里吹气
Or by spiking her drink?
难不成还从饮料下手
Timoxeline Barbebutenol.
地莫克西林巴伯布特纳
He'll enter the manic phase any moment now.
他现在随时有可能进入癫狂状态
I have to warn you that
你们可别忘了
I've been trained to resist this kind of thing.
我对抵御这类事情可是千锤百炼
You swine.
你个猪头
Agent One, what's going on?
一号特工 什么情况
He's quite harmless at this phase.
他现在没什么危害
The drug will kill him, but just before it does,
他会被毒死 不过在那之前
there'll be a short window
有一小段空档
where he'll do everything I tell him to.
我说什么他做什么
Poor Johnny.
可怜的约翰尼
You were never really Ml-7, Johnny.
你从来都不属于军情七处
You were never really one of us.
从来就不是我们的人
Now you're about to become our most famous agent.
而你现在却要成为最有名的特工了
You'll now do exactly as I tell you.
现在我说什么你做什么
You are a traitor to the Service and to your country.
你是组织和国家的叛徒
Shut her up, old chap.
让他闭嘴 老头
- Duck. - What?
- 闪 - 啥
I warned you.
跟你说了
Okay, Slater. Let's get him ready.
斯莱特 让他做好准备
Ready.
时刻准备着
Premier Ping,
总理
it's a pleasure to finally meet you.
能得相见 不胜荣幸
You had a pleasant flight, I trust?
旅途可曾安好
I was just asking the Premier if he had a pleasant flight.
我只是问总理他旅途是否安好
Kate, Johnny's back on the team.
凯特 约翰尼回归组织了
What?
什么
It's all checked out
查出来了
and the PM and the Chinese have approved it.
首相和中国方面也证实了
- Approved what? - He's standing in for Pamela.
- 证实什么 - 他来顶替帕姆拉
Isn't it great?
这不挺好吗
Excuse me. Agent Tucker.
打扰一下 塔克特工
Good, good. And your wife is well?
好的 尊夫人可好
Lock it up, Johnny.
约翰尼 把门锁了
Wonderful.
好极了
That's it.
这就对了
Premier, I am most grateful
总理 我很感谢您能在
you have agreed to meet me at this time.
这个时候同我见面
It is our pleasure.
是我荣幸
Maintain that tone, Prime Minister.
保持这种语调 首相
Avoid confrontation, keep eye contact.
避免对抗 保持眼神交流
I can assure you that the Chinese people
我可以向你保证
have always regarded the British people
中国人民一向认为贵国人民
as completely horrible.
十分神经
- Honourable. - Honourable.
- 尊敬 - 尊敬
Completely honourable.
十分值得尊敬
Of course.
当然
I was very keen to meet...
我很想见到...
Johnny, stand up and go to the water table.
约翰尼 站起来 走到饮品桌边上
Premier, I believe the present danger
总理 我相信只要及时行动起来
can be averted if we act swiftly.
当下的危险是可以避免的
Go to your right pocket.
伸手掏右口袋
We designed it for Pegasus.
这是为帕加索斯设计的
Well, it's too bloody late now.
现在太特么晚了
Just act natural.
表现得尽量自然
- Prime Minister, traditionally... - Something's wrong.
- 首相 传统意义上讲... - 不对劲
...China does not respond well to advice...
...中国并不十分接纳...
Pull out the barrel.
拔出枪管
Now, Johnny, I want you to kill Xiang Ping.
约翰尼 现在我让你杀掉向平
Oh, dear God, no.
天哪 不
He's being controlled.
他被控制了
By who?
被谁
Ambrose.
安布罗斯
Shoot Xiang Ping!
杀了他
Mind must be master of the body.
意志是身体的主人
He's resisting it.
他在抵抗
His left hand is fighting the right hand.
左手跟右手打架
Come on, Johnny.
约翰尼加油
If I can interrupt the frequency,
如果我能打乱频率的话
I could stop Ambrose from communicating with him.
就能阻止安布罗斯跟他说话
English, stand up!
英格力士 站起来
Come on. Come on.
挺住 挺住
He'll be dead in 50 seconds, sir.
五十秒后他就死了 长官
Tucker!
塔克
Come on.
快啊
- Pull the trigger! - I'm in.
- 快扣扳机 - 成功
Listen to me, this is Simon Ambrose,
听着 我是西蒙·安布罗斯
and I order you to shoot Xiang Ping!
我命令你朝向平开枪
Ten seconds, sir.
十秒
Fire!
快开枪
Go, go, go.
快进去
Time to get out of here.
快撤
Hold your fire!
别开枪
Stand down!
退下
His pulse is dropping.
脉搏越来越弱了
Don't lose him!
别放弃他
Come on, sir.
拜托 长官
Open your heart, English,
敞开心扉 英格力士
and you shall be reborn.
你会重获新生
Almost there.
差点就死了
Thank you, Kate.
谢谢你 凯特
I was passing.
吓死我了
Sir.
长官
Tucker!
塔克
Welcome back, sir.
欢迎回来 长官
Thank you, Tucker.
塔克 谢谢你
I won't kiss you, if you don't mind.
不介意的话我就不跟你亲了
Well, whatever.
无所谓啦
Where's Ambrose?
安布罗斯在哪
English?
英格力士
Sir. What are you doing, sir?
长官 你要做什么
Guideline 17-5: Never question a senior agent in the field.
行规17章第五条 别对老特工问这问那
No!
不
(您的专属情报局)
Ambrose' you five-star turd.
安布罗斯 你个十足的人渣
Another balls-up, Johnny.
约翰尼 蛋还不够疼吗
What's the matter with you?
你这什么毛病
It's all over, Ambrose.
安布罗斯 结束了
You can betray your country, you can cheat your friends,
你可以背叛祖国 出卖朋友
but you can't get away from Johnny English...
但你不能逃脱约翰尼·英格力士的法...
So long, Johnny!
别了 约翰尼
The D-7.
D-7防弹伞
The bulletproof shield!
防弹的哟
Hey! It's not working!
不管用啊
It's the T-2, sir!
那个是T-2榴弹啊
- Is he... - Oh, he's alive!
- 是... - 他还活着
It's the T-2!
是T-2
Close it. Close ii!
合上啊 合上
Stupid thing!
破玩意
Oh, Johnny.
噢 约翰尼
The T-2.
还真是T-2
Tucker, you clever boy.
塔克 人小鬼大啊
I couldn't be more delighted.
我无比的高兴
Vortex's paymasters have been arrested,
旋风组的雇主被捕了
and China has expressed its
而中国政府也表达了
gratitude to both Britain and the Service.
对英国和组织的感谢
We owe English a great deal.
我们得好好谢谢英格力士
Well, reinstating his knighthood is a truly lovely gesture.
恢复他的骑士荣誉是个积极的表示
And it will mean the world to him.
对他本人也是无上光荣
Her Majesty will be with him shortly.
女王陛下随后驾临
Gotcha! Gotcha.
还跑 看你跑
Got you!
往哪儿跑
Just about had enough of you, you old cow!
受够了 你个老妖精
You're going nowhere! Pegasus!
看你还往哪儿跑 帕加索斯
English!
英格力士
It's her! It's the killer cleaner! Finally,
就是她 就是那个清洁工杀手
I've got her!
终于被我抓到了
You never know when it's over, do you?
你还不死心是吧
Well, it's over, over, over, over, over!
看你还跑 跑 跑啊 跑
I don't know how to thank you.
无以为报啊
I'd love a take-away.
共进晚餐吧
Consider it done.
就这么定了